American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIb. 1807-1825 APS.Archives.IIb APS.Archives.IIb
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John Vaughan, [1811] March 5; Gibbs, George, 1776-1833
    Acknowlegment of receipt of A.P.S. membership diploma.
  - D[avid] Hosack to John Vaughan, March 16, 1811; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hosack, David, 1769-1835
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S. Encloses pamphlets. Suggests DeWitt Clinton as a member of the Society.
  - C[harles] P[hilibert] de Lasteyrie to the President of the A.P.S., March 18, 1811; 7 11/16" x 9 7/8"; Lasteyrie, C. de (Charles), 1759-1849
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S. his work on blue vegetable dyes. FILM199 FRAME 358
  - C[harles] P[hilibert] de Lasteyrie to the President of the A.P.S., March 18, 1811; 7 11/16" x 9 7/8"; de Lasteyrie, Charles Philibert.
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S. his work on blue vegetable dyes.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 31, 1811; 9-1/2x7; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p.and end. In French. Sends the poem on astronomy by M.Gudin, and suggests he be made a member; sends copies of some of his own works. Film 403 Frame 53
  - William Bentley to John Vaughan, Salem, Mass., April 15, 1811; 7 5/8" x 8 7/8"; Bentley, William, 1759-1819
    1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1811 April 17; Hamilton, Paul
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1811 April 24; Johnson, William, Jr.
    Encloses $10.00 admission fee to the A.P.S..
  - Report of a committee on a paper on a saltpetre cave (Mammoth Cave) in Kentucky, by Fred.Ridgely, May 17, 1811; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.:Zaccheus Collins,S.Godon and Charles J.Wister. 2p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.428. For paper, see letter from Ridgely to B.Rush; March 15, 1811.
  - W[illia]m Jones to the American Philosophical Society, May 17, 1811; 7 7/8" x 12 7/8"; Jones, William, 1760-1831
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. William Jones of Philadelphia presents to the A.P.S. the image of the Hindu god of wisdom, sent to him by William Jones of Calcutta.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, librarian of APS, June 10, 1811; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Peck, William Dandridge, 1763-1822
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and end. and enc. - 1p. Acknowledges seeds; encloses list of names of some of them.
  - And[re]w Ellicott to John Vaughan, June 24, 1811; 6" x 7 1/2"; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820
    Lancaster, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Intends to communicate to the A.P.S. all astronomical and meteorological observations made in the course of his southerntrip.
  - Report of the [Committee] upon a plan for organizing a committee for making researches into and collecting materials for the history of the United States, July 5, 1811; 7 7/8" x 13"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 4 pp. Dr.D. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 429.
  - R[obert] M. Patterson to John Vaughan, July 7, 1811; 7 3/8" x 9"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Is sending books from Paris for Mr. Michaux, Mr. Walsh, and the A.P.S.
  - Horatio G. Spafford to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 11, 1811; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Spafford, Horatio Gates, 1778-1832
    Albany, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Desires to know rules relating to the election of members to the A.P.S. Has "some papers which I think of offering some such association... "
  - Levett Harris to John Vaughan, July 17, 1811; 8" x 9 11/16"; Harris, Levett
    St. Petersburg, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: two dictionaries and two grammars, "the best that have appeared."
  - Levett Harris to John Vaughan, July 17, 1811; 7 7/8" x 9 3/8"; Harris, Levett
    St. Petersburg, 2 pp. L. Copy. Sends to the A.P.S.: two dictionaries and two grammars, "the best that have appeared."
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, July 24, 1811; 6 3/4" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. Requests assistance of Mr. Vaughan in discounting a note for $400.
  - Levett Harris to ----, August 28, 1811; 7 11/16" x 9 3/8"; Harris, Levett
    St. Petersburg, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S., in the name of Professor [Frederick] Adelung, a copy of the latter's Russian dictionary and grammar.
  - John Quincy Adams to John Vaughan, Secretary to the A.P.S., September 15, 1811; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    St. Petersburg, 1 p. and endorsement. Transmits to the A.P.S. a recent publication by Gotthelf Fischer upon mineralogy. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 431, November 15, 1811.
  - Letter to [American philosophical society], Oct. 21, 1811; 7" x 9 1/4"; Destutt de Tracy, Antoine Louis Claude, comte, 1754-1836
    Paris, Oct. 21, 1811. A.L.S. 2p. an end. In French. Although he has never received notice of his nomination, he has heard from many persons and seen in Vol.6 of the Transactions of his election to membership in 1804. Expresses appreciation for honor. Presents various works. Mentions Lafayette, Cabanis, and Warden.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, October 24, 1811; 7 3/8" x 9 1/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. "...I have executed all your commissions and instructions. I delivered the sum of one hundred and twenty Dollars to our friend Michaux..."
  - Letter to [Gotthilf Heinrich Ernst Mühlenberg?], Nov. 17, 1811; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Palisot de Beauvois, Ambrose-Marie-François-Joseph, 1752-1820
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. Enc.of 3p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural History, vol.I,no.48.) Encloses list of mosses received from him. Concerning American mosses.
  - C[harles] W[illson] Peale to the [American] Philosophical Society, November 29, 1811; 8" x 10 1/8"; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Museum, Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. In order to consolidate museum, requests to be relieved of unexpired term of lease of room in Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Dec. 19, 1811; 8x6-1/2; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Introducing Correa da Serra. Hopes that the APS has received Turgot's Works which he forwarded. Film 403 Frame 54
  - Memorandum relative to old donations and communications, , 1811; 8 1/8" x 13 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], ----, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, January 16, 1812; 4 3/4" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of $55.00.
  - Letter to Thomas T. Hewson, Jan. 26, 1812; 7 1/4" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges re-election as president of the A.P.S. Bur. of rolls,V.6,215-S.2,v.45,192. FILM 199 FRAME 180
  - Note as to donation to the A.P.S., February 7, 1812; 5 1/4" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    by Joseph Anthony, of the "Original Charter of Privileges from William Penn to the People of the Province of Pennsylvania." [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 432.
  - Report of the committee appointed on Mr. [Charles Willson] Peale's proposal to give up the lease provided the Society can find another tenant., February 7, 1812; 8 1/4" x 13 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Jn. Vaughan and R. Patterson. Terms of conditional contract with Mr. [Thomas] Sully.
  - Report of the committee appointed to wait on Mr. Joseph Anthony, February 7, 1812; 7 3/4" x 9 11/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: W[illia]m Tilghman, Peter S. DuPonceau. In re presentation to the A.P.S. of the original charter granted by William Penn to the people of Pennsylvania, 1701.
  - Opinion of Peter S. DuPonceau upon the legal right of the American Philosophical Society to lease certain rooms in Philosophical Hall to a painter for the pratice of his profession., February 10, 1812; 8 1/8" x 13 1/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 5 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau. Affirmative opinion.
  - Letter to Benjamin S. Barton, Feb. 10, 1812; 10x8; Montgomery, Alexander, d. 1813
    Frankfort, Ky., A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 45.) Concerning local earthquakes. Cf. Minutes, p.434.
  - Report of committee appointed to inquire into the propriety of letting to Mr. [Thomas] Sully the vacant rooms in the Society's building... [Philadelphia], February 21, 1812; 7 3/4" x 8 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. D.S.: Jn. Vaughan, R. Patterson, Zaccheus Collins, Peter S. Duponceau. Favorable report.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the communication of Captain Patridge on the height of the White mountains, February 21, 1812; 7 3/4" x 8 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Benjamin Allen, R[obert] Patterson. Publication recommended.
  - [Terms of] lease to [Thomas Sully?]., February, 1812; 4 3/4" x 7 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia,] 1 p. D. Unsigned. Fragment only.
  - American Philosophical Society to [Thomas] Sully, February, 1812; 7 3/4" x 12 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], n.d., but ca. 1 p. Dr.D. Unsigned. Form of lease of roams in Philosophical Hall to Thomas Sully for a term of five years. Dates not filled in.
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, March 7, 1812; 4 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of $146.00.
  - Society of Antiquaries of London to John Vaughan, March 9, 1812; 7 3/8" x 8 3/4"; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Librarian of A.P.S., Somerset Place, [London], 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle, Secretary. Presents to the A.P.S.: Archaeologia XVI, pt. 2.
  - Letter to Josef Franco. de Caldas, Bogota, March 12, 1812; 10x8; Grassi, Giovanni, 1775-1849
    Georgetown, Md., A.L.S. 2p., and add., end. In French. (see Ms. comm. to the A.P.S. Math. and astronomy, vol. 2, no. 79.) Astronomical matters.
  - N(icholas) Biddle to John Vaughan, March 15, 1812; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is leaving for Lancaster, and therefore returns book.
  - J[oel] Barlow to John Vaughan, April 17, 1812; 8" x 10 1/16"; Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812
    Paris, 2pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is forwarding to the A.P.S. "a few books & pamphlets." Thinks [Alexander] Wilson could sell a dozen copies of his American Ornithology in Paris. FILM 403 FRAME 15
  - Henry Muhlenberg to John Vaughan, May 10, 1812; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Muhlenberg, Henry, 1753-1815
    Lancaster, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Friendship with "Mr. Correa" (de Serra). Varied activities. Botanical matters.
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, June 6, 1812; 4 15/16" x 5 3/4"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning loan of $25 to Jane Aitken.
  - Report of the board of officers to whom was referred Dr. [Benjamin Smith] Barton's memoir upon the late Jonathan B. Smith, July 10, 1812; 8" x 9 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 435.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, July 25, 1812; 5" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of $50.00.
  - D[avid] Hosack to John Vaughan, August 14, 1812; 7 3/4" x 9 11/16"; Hosack, David, 1769-1835
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: American medical and philosophical register, I and II. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 436.
  - Talbot Hamilton to Jno. Vaughan, September 1, 1812; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Hamilton, Talbot
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S. some sand and dust, "consequent upon the eruptions at the Island of St. Vincent." See Minutes, September 18, 1812, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 436.
  - Jno. C. Lowber to John Vaughan, September 18, 1812; 7 1/16" x 7 3/4"; Lowber, John C. (John Cole), 1789-1834
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents the A.P.S. with a copy of the Ordinances of the city of Philadelphia.
  - W(illiam) Short to J(ohn) Vaughan, October 5, (1812?); Short, William, 1759-1849
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards catalogue (of what?) to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Dr. J[ames] Mease, Oct. 18, 1812; Svin'in, Pavel Petrovich, 1788-1839
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p., end. Sends Karamsin's Pantheon of the Russian poets for the American philosophical society; translates the description of Lomonossoff. Cf. APS minutes Nov. 6,1812.
  - Report of the librarian upon papers or communications directed to be published, November 6, 1812; 7 7/8" X12 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 4 pp. D. Covers the period from December 21, 1804. Mentions "Bust of Jefferson." FILM 199 FRAME 359
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, December 3, 1812; 4 7/8" x 7 5/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of $36.00.
  - Memorandum of papers which appear from the minutes to be in order for publication, December 4, 1812; 7 3/4" x 12 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia,?] 2 pp. and endorsement. D.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 11, 1812; 9-1/2x8; Godon, Silvain, ca. 1774-1840
    Philadelphia prison, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning work on natural history.
  - Report of committee on J.W.'s paper on insects with additional information by B. S. Barton, Dec. 18, 1812; 10x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: J.Correa de Serra and Thos.T.Hewson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.438. For paper, see: J.W. Observations on the Phalaeena tinea,etc.; Nov. 1, 1812.
  - Royal society of Edinburgh to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 29, 1812; 7 1/8" x 8 7/8"; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S.: Thomas Allan. Presents to the A.P.S.: Royal Society of Edinburgh, Transactions, VI. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 440.
  - W[illia]m Vaughan to the President of the [American] Philosophical Society, December 29, 1812; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Hebe. FILM 199 FRAME 360
  - Letter to [American philosophical society ?], Jan. 12, 1813; 8" x 10"; Bécourt, R. de
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Solicits aid for publication of certain works.
  - Letter to [P.S.] Duponceau, Jan. 12, 1813; 8" x 10"; Bécourt, R. de
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. In French. Encloses letter to be forwarded to the company [APS ?].
  - John Melish to [John] Vaughan, February 5, 1813; 4 7/8" x 7 5/8"; Melish, John, 1771-1822
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a copy of his Travels in the United States of America.
  - Report of committee on [Benjamin Smith] Barton's paper on insects, Feb. 19, 1813; 7x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Thos. T. Hewson, Zaccheus Collins and Correa de Serra. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.439. For paper, see: Barton, B.S. Additional information...; Dec. 16, 1812.
  - William Johns to Jno. Vaughan, March 22, 1813; 7 1/8" x 8 7/8"; Jones, William
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Manchester, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. The secretary of the Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester transmits to the A.P.S. their Memoirs, n.s., II.
  - Charles Smith to [John] Vaughan, April 5, 1813; 7 5/16" x 9 7/8"; Smith, Charles, 1765-1836
    Lancaster, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to deliver to the A.P.S.: Laws of Pennsylvania, V, if it is not already in their possession.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a communication on the tuition of ladies, by the Rev. Timothy Alden, April 16, 1813; 7 7/8" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1p. and endorsement. D.S.: W[illia]m Staughton, Ja[me]s Abercrombie. The contents of the communication does not come "within the objects of the Society."
  - New regulations ... proposed by B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton and John Redman Coxe, May 8, 1813; 4 1/2" x 7 1/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: John Redman Coxe, B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton. Five regulations listed.
  - Joseph Worrell and W[illia]m Broome to [John] Vaughan, May 19, 1813; 7 7/8" x 8"; Worrell, Joseph, 1757-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. D.S. Estimate of value of certain fixtures in Philosophical Hall.
  - Report of F[rancis] Nichols concerning expenses of publishing the next volume of A.P.S. Transactions, 1813 June 18; American Philosophical Society.
    Francis Nichols' report concerning the expenses for publishing the next volume of the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Vaughan, July 6, 1813; 7 7/8" x 10"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: Royal Horticultural Society, Transactions, II, pt. 1. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 442.
  - W. Staughton to Revd. J(ohn) Vaughan, July 9, 1813; 4 3/4" x 7 7/8"; Staughton, W.
    ----, 1 p. A.L.S. Returns books borrowed from Vaughan, thanking him for use of the same.
  - S(amuel) Higginson to John Vaughan, August 30, 1813; 7 11/16" x 9 3/4"; Higginson, Samuel
    Boston, 4 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Respecting Stewart's portrait of Dr. Priestley.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s C. James, Philadelphia, Sept. 11, 1813; 10x8; Stockler, Francisco de Borja Garçaõ
    Rio de Janiero, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards volume.
  - J. Correa de Serra to John Vaughan, September 27, 1813; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Correia da Serra, José Francesco, 1750-1823
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Personal affairs. Intends to return to Philadelphia and finish paper for the A.P.S. Copy of letter printed in A.P.S. Trans.v.45, part 2, p. 126.
  - Report of the committee appointed to report on a paper by the late Doctor [Benjamin] Franklin, October 1, 1813; 7 11/16" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "Meteorological imaginations and conjectures", Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterton, Jon[athan] Williams. Report paper as already published. FILM 54-61 FRAME 127
  - J[ohn] C. Warren to John Vaughan, October 6, 1813; 7 5/8" x 9 5/16"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. May, the bearer of a set of the publications of the Massachusetts Medical Society, to be presented to the A.P.S.
  - Thomas Allan to the Secretary of A.P.S., January 18, 1814; 7 1/8" x 9 13/16"; Allan, Thomas, 1777-1833
    Edinburgh, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presented to the A.P.S.: Royal Society of Edinburgh, Transactions, VII. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 448.
  - Letter to R.M. Patterson, Jan.20, 1814; 7 3/4" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges re-election as president of the A.P.S. Printed: Bergh, V.14,70. Bur. of rolls, V.6,366-S.1,v.13,249. FILM 199 FRAME 181
  - List of books belonging to American Philosophical Society, January 27, 1814; 8 1/8" x 13 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    out. [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.
  - Report of committee on paper by Charles Varle on yellow fever, Feb. 18, 1814; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Reuben Haines, R.Patterson and Jn. Vaughan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, pp.443-444.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, February 26, 1814; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. a copy of his Essay of consular establishments, together with various other works.
  - Josiah Quincy to ----, March 1, 1814; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Quincy, Josiah
    Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Memoirs of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, III, pt. 1.
  - Jac(ob) Savage to John Vaughan, March 3, 1814; 7 1/2" x 10"; Savage, Jacob
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards two of Mr. Buckminster's sermons; will send two more by the next mail.
  - R[edwood] Fisher to John Vaughan, March 4, 1814; 4 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Fisher, Redwood, 1782-1856
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: James Cutbush, American artist's manual, 2 vols. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 444.
  - Tho[mas] C. James to John Vaughan, March 4, 1814; 7 15/16" x 8 15/16"; James, Thomas C. (Thomas Chalkley), 1766-1835
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: John Burns, Principles of midwifery. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 444.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 18, 1814; 8x5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Donates a Jefferson publication to the library.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for books purchased, March 30, 1814; 10x8; Farrand, P.
    D.S.: Joseph Simmons. 1p.
  - Report of the committee appointed to cause the constitution and bye-laws of the Society to be printed, April 1, 1814; 6 5/8" x 7 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Jona[than] Williams, R[obert] Patterson. See Pro., "XXII, pt. 3, 445.
  - Report of committee on Joshua Humphreys' paper on a pump, April 15, 1814; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M. Patterson, William Hembel, jr. and Jon. Williams. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.445. For paper, see letter from Joshua Humphreys to J.Vaughan, March 25, 1814.
  - Society of Antiquaries of London to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 16, 1814; 7 1/8" x 8 3/4"; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Somerset Place, [London], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle, Secretary. Presents to the A.P.S.: Archaeologia, XVII. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 448.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a memoir from Mr. [Joseph] Cloud, June 10, 1814; 7 11/16" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    on the fusing temperature of metals, [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, William Hembel, Jr. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - B(enjamin) H(enry) Latrobe to Jo(hn) Vaughan, June 19, 1814; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    Pittsburg, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Quarrel about Oliver Evans's engine. FILM403 FRAME2.2
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, June 24, 1814; 13x8; Lambert, William
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. (see Ms. Comm. to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 2, no. 85.) Correction of the calendar.
  - Report of committee on De Bretton's paper on nervous irritability, July 15, 1814; 8-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: B.S. Barton, C. Wistar and Thos. T. Hewson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.447.
  - J[oseph] G. Swift to Thomas C. James, July 20, 1814; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Swift, J. G. (Joseph Gardner), 1783-1865
    New York, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - DeWitt Clinton to R[obert] M. Patterson, July 21, 1814; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Clinton, D. (DeWitt)
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - To John Gummere, 1814 16 Aug.; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Letter and receipt for $10.00 dues.
  - Report of committee on [Elisha] De Butts' paper on thermometers, Aug. 20, 1814; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Adam Seybert, B.S.Barton and Jos. Cloud. 1p.and end. Printed: Trans., n.s., vol. I, 301 ff.
  - John W. Francis to J[ohn] Vaughan, September 5, 1814; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Francis, John W. (John Wakefield), 1789-1861